Just a reminder, this is what our final exercise looks like, we can select different languages
here and then go and hit the GitHub search API and display the results.
Pretty straightforward, flask app, there's no, we're not using a database here, we're
not really maintaining any state, we're just checking what the user checked and unchecked
the feature request.
Pretty easy peasy.
Now let's go through how to implement this.
I'm going to exit out of the development server that I was using and I'm going to run
a command to call tree that's going to list the directory structure for this chapter.
If you're on Mac OS, just know that this utility doesn't come with Mac, you have to install
it.
So at the root, we have API.py, I have exceptions.py, where I put my custom exception.
I have models.py, where I put the model that stores my GitHub repository.
Then I have a static folder with a faevacon from my website, CSS styles that I've provided
for you.
Please don't get the pitchforks out if my CSS isn't good, I'm one of those full stack developers.
But then we have a few templates.
We have a template for an error page and a template for our index page, as well as some tests
that we can run.
Let's go through and look at these files.
Our exception.py file is pretty straightforward.
I have a class here and like you saw before it, inherits from exception.
In the constructor, I'm taking a status code.
If the status code was for a three, it's going to say rate limit reached.
If the status code was any other type of error status code, it's going to print that out.
Then I pass this new modified message that I created to a super dot in it.
Looking at the model's file, we live coded this earlier.
This class, the GitHub repo class, is used to represent a single GitHub repository.
In my constructor, I take the name, the language, the number of stars.
I also return a handy string representation and a wrapper.
Now looking at API.py.
This is where I put my create query and my repos with most stars methods.
Remember that we were methods that look almost exactly like this in the intro to Python final exercise.
Going through these for creating a query, I take a list of languages and the minimum amount of stars.
In yesterday's code, we were looping over each query adding it on to the string,
using concatenate, using the string join is much more efficient.
Concatenate is a string concatenation is a pretty inefficient operation and using string join as much faster.
Now we can make that same query using an F string for language, going through each language and languages,
stripping out any trailing or leading white space, and then creating our new query with just one concatenation and concatenating the minimum number of stars that we'd like to see.
Now in the re-boes with most stars method, we get our query by using that query method.
We have the same parameters, I've printed them out here, but you don't need to do that in your code.
I get the response by using the request library to get the resource at this GitHub API search URL, passing in the parameters I set up.
Now if the status code was not 200, that means if anything went wrong, I'm just going to raise instance of my GitHub API exception,
passing in the response.status code.
Next, I get the JSON from the response, I get the items at the items key, and I'm just going to use a list comprehension to return an instance of my GitHub repo.
A list of instances of my GitHub repo class, passing in the name, the language, and the Stargazers count, and using a list comprehension to do that for each item in items.
Notice there is no main method here, we're not running our code in the same file, instead we're going to be using this as a library from our Flask app.
We're scrolling to the top, notice that we imported requests so that we can use it as an available library.
We're also importing a few things from our own custom classes, so our GitHub API exception and our GitHub repo model.
Those are all the building blocks.
Now open app.py, and see how it all gets put together.
For you Windows folks, I'm going to, I'm going to put in additional instructions here to see who have them in one place with the final exercise.
But we have a few imports here as well, we're importing a few things from Flask where importing the Flask class, we're importing render template.
And we're also importing something called request, which gives us information about the request that we are currently processing.
For my API, I'm also importing this repo with most stars, method, and I'm importing my GitHub API exception, so that I can catch it, do something with it.
I'm creating a new app, a new Flask app here by passing in a Dundername, and then a making a list of available languages that I want my users of my web application to be able to choose from.